

Bruce Page

17830 Virginia Avenue Hagerstown, MD 21740 (301) 730.9365 rbrucepage@yahoo.com

SUMMARY:

Front-end creative expert with 14+ years experience building Web applications & mobile-friendly E-commerce & promotional websites. Regular use of latest HTML5/CSS3/JS coding methods and thorough understanding of all relevant software packages. Growing online business through creative thinking, strategic planning and execution of strong, relevant and non-intrusive user experiences.

EDUCATION:

John Herron School of Art and Design, Indiana University | 1997 - 2000

BFA - Visual Communication

WORK HISTORY:

Sevatec, Inc. :: Martinsburg, WV | 3/12 - current

Senior Consultant, UI Specialist

- Developing the User Interface for DOJ/ATF's eTrace 5.0 software. Working with local and remote stakeholders to ensure software is optimized for every day use by thousands of registered law enforcement agents and firearm tracing professionals.
- Meet regularly with ATF personnel, and development teams to define application requirements. Requirements drive application prototypes. Prototypes are used to guide development.

The Big Idea Supply Company :: Hagerstown, MD | 2/08 - current

Creative Director, Principal

- Develop compelling user-centric interfaces that are easy to both understand and use.
- Partner with clients to create engaging and unique concepts and strategies.
- Provide consultation to those needing the help getting their creative, regardless of medium, to the next level.
- Create engaging UI that communicate to, and steer a user, but gets out of the way, and encourages interaction.



Bruce Page

17830 Virginia Avenue Hagerstown, MD 21740 (301) 730.9365 rbrucepage@yahoo.com

Healthy Directions, LLC :: Potomac, MD | 4/04 – 3/12

Executive Director, Web Design

- Oversee all aspects of HD's internal creative web design agency.
- Design, and lead a team of designers, in the development of 200 online creative projects per month.
- Collaborate with internal and external stakeholders to develop best-in-class online collateral including: E-commerce and promotional websites, E-newsletters, landing pages, rich media banner placement, broadcast emails, Social marketing efforts and online streaming media through all possible Internet communication channels including PPC campaigns and affiliate relationships.
 - Ensure implementations are timely and effective per brand guidelines, statistical analysis and user experience best practices.
- Implement state-of-the art content management tools + work with ECP vendors to ensure smooth platform migrations. Create requirements and test plans to verify platform is optimized for performance and results.
- Partner with other business leaders to brainstorm, develop, and execute creative business strategies.
- QA websites to verify coding best practices are being applied and maintained. Facilitate SEO optimization, accessibility standards compliance and full browser support in all desktop and mobile environments. Provide recommendations and manage updates if modifications are required.
- Oversee development of SOPs to maintain transparent communication of current processes and provide reference materials to design teams.
- Create cohesive team environment & facilitate growth through mentoring, regular internal training sessions, 1:1 weeklies with individual team members, benchmarking exercises and critiquing, off-site courses and conferences, and goal setting with regular progress check-ins.
- Provide creative consultation to Executive management as it pertains to ways we might leverage the Internet to expand business opportunities. Recommendations are regularly implemented and successful.



Bruce Page

17830 Virginia Avenue Hagerstown, MD 21740 (301) 730.9365 rbrucepage@yahoo.com

Kaplan University :: Hagerstown, MD | 7/02 - 4/04

Full-Time Instructor

- Instructed a variety of classes on software packages including Adobe Photoshop, Premier, Illustrator and Flash.
- Instructed several courses on principals of graphic design, digital video production and color theory.
- Responsible for recommending software, installing and maintaining on 45+ Apple computers and file servers across the college's internal network.
- Enhanced management skills through regular team building exercises and inherent student management responsibilities.
- Was recognized as a top instructor in the Graphics department, based on end-of-semester student evaluation feedback for 3 consecutive semesters.

Ellipsis Design :: Hagerstown, MD | 12/02 - 4/04

Creative Director | Partner

- Responsible for all creative executions presented to clients. Managed junior designer.
- Specked out projects and provided LOE assessments and quotes based on project requirements.
- Managed, built and retained relationships working 1:1 with clients.
- Worked with external vendors to deliver print and online-based collateral in various formats, always on time and within budget.
- Active member of the deign community. Joined AIGA and participated in numerous events.
- Managed all aspects of the business, including: taxes, payroll, legal and accounting consultation, business marketing and networking, Business incorporation.
- Aimed to exceed client expectations. Regularly received accolades from customers.
 Me being easy to work with was a regular complement, and reason why I was requested on projects often.



Bruce Page

17830 Virginia Avenue Hagerstown, MD 21740 (301) 730.9365 rbrucepage@yahoo.com

mediumFUSION, LLC Graphic Arts Group :: Indianapolis, IN | 2/01 – 5/02

Art Director

- Responsible for creative executions presented to clients.
- Specked out projects and provided LOE assessments and quotes based on project requirements.
- Managed, built and retained relationships working 1:1 with clients.
- Worked with external vendors to deliver print and online-based collateral in various formats, always on time and within budget.
- Designed and developed all online and video creative.

Career Note: Additional experience: Adjunct Professor, John Herron School of Art | Indianapolis, IN: Fall 1998, 2001 – 2002 • Art Director, Robert Feldman and Associates | Bethesda, MD: 2000 – 2001

Internships: Indiana Pacers | Conseco Fieldhouse: Interior and Display Design | designer, 1998–1999 Iris Centre for Digital Arts: Advertising and Marketing | designer, 1999 North Street Media: Advertising and Marketing | web designer, 2000

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Software

Adobe Creative Suite, Coda, Transmit, Fetch or any FTP app, MS Office Suite, Dropbox

CMSs

Ektron 400, Joomla!, Magento, OpenWeb, Wordpress, Drupal, WebLinc Direct, StrongMail

Code and such

Hand-coded HTML(5), CSS(3), JS, jQuery, a little PHP, a little ASP, responsive coding methods, E-commerce design, HTML E-mail best practices including ESP delivery, Return Path testing and data mining, creative team management, Illustration, photography, printing processes... almost anything tied to visual communication.